Hey, Brett Contras here and just wanted
to film a video showing everything about
the glute ham race. So, this one I got
from Elite Fitness. Um, I've had it for
probably around say 5 years or so, so
I've kind of learned uh all the little
bells and whistles to it. But, um,
there's two different places you can
adjust. You can adjust this up and down.
And most powerlifters and most athletes
I see will have it it down here. And
I've never liked having it down here.
I've always liked having this um foot
play up as high as you can. I've always
felt it more in my hamstrings, which
actually makes sense when you think
about it because up top you the angle
allows for a little bit more constant
tension. Not much, but I've always liked
having it up here. And then you can also
play with the lever length right here.
Now, if I have it closer to the pad,
then my knees will be up here. Um, for
some people that they can't tolerate
this the stress, just the the the
physical trauma that it puts on their
knees. But I can do this, but this would
extend the lever length because my knees
are now here and I wouldn't be able to
get as many reps. So, I'll show you um
I'll show you what that looks like. So,
if I'm way out here now, my look how far
my knees are. Now, from here, it's
really hard to do a glute ham raise. So,
um if I have it out here, I can only get
like five five reps. But if I put it out
further
at hole five, that last one was at hole
three. This one's a hole five. Now, my
knees stay about here. So, I've got some
of my um thighs touching, which
decreases the lever arm length, and it
also lets my knees sink down a little
bit. And so, now I can get more reps
this way. So, from here,
a lot easier. I can get around between
12 and 20 reps that way. So once you get
really good at the glute ham raise, you
want to make it harder because you know
these I can bust out
depending on where it is in my workout.
I can bust out a lot of reps. So I'm
going to show you four different ways
how to make it harder. Um the first way
is to just toy around with your arm
placement. If my arms are down here, um,
I've got a lot of weight. You know, my
weight, the weight of my arms is down
low. But if I move it up here or even
here, that's a lot of weight. You're
putting further down the lever. So, it's
a big deal. Kind of like doing a lateral
raise like this. And doing a lateral
raise like this is a lot harder. The
further the weight is down the lever,
the harder it's going to be. So, um, I
found that from this to this is around
the same difference as holding on to
around a 30 lb dumbbell right here. A 20
to 30 lb dumbbell. So, makes a big
difference. So, this would be like maybe
a prisoner. You could call it like a
prisoner incl.
So, here's a one. The first way to make
it way harder is to just here
to there.
Okay. Next way is to hold on to a
dumbbell,
which I just do right here.
Here's a 20 caler.
And I keep it right beneath my chin.
Okay. Okay. And then the final way, um,
actually not the final way, I'll show
two different ways, would be to put a
band around your neck, this one has this
nice little these rings for band
attachments, but the nice thing about
the band is that it gives you constant
tension. Um, up top the glue he is
unloaded. So right here there's not much
tension, but up top there's a lot. So
here's the band.
So right here it's pulling me down.
And then of course the hardest variation
would be a dumbbell and a band
which
[Music]
that's really hard. Okay. And then
finally
um I learned this from Smitty um from
the diesel group. Um, but this is
something I've been thinking about for a
while. I just never got around to trying
it. He elevated the back of the glue ham
raise. Put this at an angle. I have
another video on my YouTube page that
shows this and he does, too. But if you
if you put this back
um
backside up onto a bench or something.
So, I elevated around an angle like
this. And um then what that does is it
puts now you're at an angle. So as you
come up
there's constant tension here. The only
problem with the good ham race is that
right here.
It's pretty much unloaded on my hammies.
My hammies aren't doing much. You know,
my low back is trying to extend to keep
me more upright. But um if you have this
at an angle now you have constant
tension and it's a lot more effective
exercise. I found that if I can do
around say u three sets of 12 at the end
of my workout. If I do at the beginning
I could probably get three sets of 20.
But say I do three sets of 12 um at the
end of my workout. If I were to do the
constant tension glue ham raids at an
angle I can only get around three sets
of six. So it makes it that much harder
and you feel it a lot more in the
hammies. So anyway, that's all about the
glue ham race. Hope you liked it.